vine.co 2019-06-24

# Privacy Policy — Vine

## Vine Archive - Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy describes how and when Twitter, Inc. and Twitter International Company (collectively, **“Twitter”** ), collect, use, and share your information when you use the Vine Archive or otherwise access videos, information, text, graphics, photos, and other materials that users previously posted publicly on Vine (collectively referred to as **“Content”** ) on the Vine Archive. When using the Vine Archive, you acknowledge the practices and policies described in this Privacy Policy. As of the effective date of this policy, you will only be able to access archives of Content, in accordance with our [Terms of Service](https://vine.co/tos) ( **“Terms”** ), that users previously posted publicly on Vine. All other features of The Vine Archive, including the ability to create a Vine account, log into an account, and post new Content, are disabled and we retain no non-public user information except for information necessary to display Content and otherwise operate the Vine Archive. 

### Information Collection

  * **Public Content:** Vine was a video sharing platform through which users were able to share videos and profile information, among other information, with a wide range of users and other services that accessed Vine. Certain public profile information, such as Vine handles and videos, continues to be available publicly on the Vine Archive. We do not update the Vine Archive and you no longer have the ability to post new Content. Twitter will generally continue to host this information until we receive a request to delete such data in accordance with the instructions provided below or as required by law (see **“Deleting Your Personal Information”** below).
  * **Personal Information You Provide:** You may provide personal information to us, for example when you request customer support or otherwise communicate with us. The types of information we may collect include your name, email address, and any other information you choose to provide. We use this information to respond to your questions or concerns. The Vine Archive does not allow the submission of personal information.
  * **Log Data:** Our servers automatically record information ( **"Log Data"** ) created by your use of the Vine Archive, such as when you view Content hosted by Twitter. Log Data may include information such as your IP address, browser type, or operating system. Twitter uses Log Data for troubleshooting and related activities necessary to maintain the the Vine Archive.

### Purposes and Legal Bases

We use information we receive from you for the purposes described below, except where restricted by law. In doing so, Twitter relies on its legitimate interests to lawfully process such data:

  * **Archiving Content in the Public Interest:** Twitter hosts the Vine Archive, which contains Content people chose to publicly share. We do this to preserve our users’ historic speech and to preserve access to Content that was publicly posted on the internet. This furthers our users’ right to free expression and the right of members of the public to access public speech. We generally remove Content where requested by the individual who posted it (see **“Deleting Your Personal Information/Your Rights”** below). 
  * **Operating Our Site:** Twitter may also use your information as necessary to pursue our legitimate interests of enforcing our Terms and preventing unlawful activities and misuse of the Vine Archive; protecting the legal rights, property, safety, and security of Twitter and our users; and resolving disputes involving you relating to the Vine Archive. Twitter may also use your personal information where reasonably necessary to comply with applicable laws, regulations, legal process, or governmental requests. 

### Information Sharing and Disclosure

  * **User-Controlled Sharing:** Content on the Vine Archive can be collected and used by others and redistributed through the internet and other media channels. 
  * **Service Providers:** We engage service providers to perform functions and provide the Vine Archive to us in the United States, Ireland, and other countries. We may share information with such service providers on the condition that they use the data only on our behalf, pursuant to our instructions, and subject to confidentiality obligations consistent with this Privacy Policy. 
  * **Law and Harm:** Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this Policy, we may preserve or disclose your information if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect our rights or property. However, nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to limit any legal defenses or objections that you may have to a third party's, including a government's, request to disclose your information. 
  * **Change of Ownership and Affiliates:** In the event Twitter is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization, or sale of assets, information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. The promises in this Privacy Policy will apply to information as transferred to the new entity. We may also disclose information to our corporate affiliates in order to help operate our services and our affiliates’ services. 
  * **Non-Personal Information:** We may share or disclose aggregated or otherwise non-personal information. 

### Our Global Operations and Privacy Shield

To bring you our services, we operate globally. Where the laws of your country allow you to do so, you authorize us to transfer, store, and use your data in the United States, Ireland, and any other country where we operate. In some of the countries to which we transfer personal data, the privacy and data protection laws and rules regarding when government authorities may access data may vary from those of your country. Learn more about our global operations and data transfer [here](https://help.twitter.com/rules-and-policies/global-operations-and-data-transfer). 

When we transfer personal data outside of the European Union or EFTA States, we ensure an adequate level of protection for the rights of data subjects based on the adequacy of the receiving country’s data protection laws, contractual obligations placed on the recipient of the data (model clauses may be requested by inquiry as described below), or EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield principles.

Twitter, Inc. complies with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield principles (the “Principles”) regarding the collection, use, sharing, and retention of personal data from the European Union and Switzerland, as described in our [EU-US Privacy Shield certification and Swiss-US Privacy Shield certification](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TORzAAO).

If you have a Privacy Shield-related complaint, please contact us [here](https://help.twitter.com/forms/privacy). As part of our participation in Privacy Shield, if you have a dispute with us about our adherence to the Principles, we will seek to resolve it through our internal complaint resolution process, alternatively through the independent dispute resolution body [JAMS](https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield), and under certain conditions, through the [Privacy Shield arbitration process.](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=G-Arbitration-Procedures)

Privacy Shield participants are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the US Federal Trade Commission and other authorized statutory bodies. Under certain circumstances, participants may be liable for the transfer of personal data from the EU or Switzerland to third parties outside the EU and Switzerland. Learn more about the EU-US Privacy Shield and Swiss-US Privacy Shield [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome). 

### Retention

Since the Vine Archive is an archive of public Content, we hope (but assume no obligation) to maintain this Content indefinitely. If not already done earlier, we will delete Log Data after 30 days. 

### Deleting Your Personal Information / Your Rights

If you reside in certain territories, including the European Union or EFTA States, you benefit from a number of rights in relation to your information. While some of these rights apply generally, certain rights apply only in certain limited cases. We describe these rights below: 

  * **Access.** The Content we process in relation to the the Vine Archive is public, so it can be freely accessed online. 
  * **Change, Restrict, Delete.** You may also have rights to change, restrict our use of, or delete your personal data. As the data we hold is archived, we may be limited in our ability to change or restrict the use of your data. However, absent exceptional circumstances (like where we are required to store data for legal reasons) we will generally delete your personal data upon request. To request the deletion of your data please contact us at [vinehelp@twitter.com.](mailto:vinehelp.twitter.com)
  * **Object.** As we process your information based on our legitimate interests, you can object to this processing in certain circumstances. In such cases, we will delete your personal data unless we have compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing or where it is needed for legal reasons.
  * **Complain.** If you reside in the European Union or EFTA States, should you wish to raise a concern about our use of your information (and without prejudice to any other rights you may have), you have the right to do so with your local data protection authority, or with the Irish Data Protection Commissioner whose contact details can be found [here](https://www.dataprotection.ie/docs/Contact-us/b/11.htm).

### Our Policy Towards Children

The Vine Archive is not directed to persons under 16. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. If we become aware that a child under 16 has provided us with personal data, we will delete such information from our systems.

### Changes to this Policy

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time for any reason. Each version will apply to information collected while it was in place. We will notify you of any material changes to our Privacy Policy by posting the new Privacy Policy on our website. You are advised to consult this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes.

### Contact Us

Thoughts or questions about this Privacy Policy? Please let us know by contacting us [here](https://help.twitter.com/forms/privacy) or writing to us at the appropriate address below. 

Twitter, Inc.   
Attn: Privacy Policy Inquiry   
1355 Market St., Suite 900   
San Francisco, CA 94103 

If you live outside the United States, the data controller is Twitter International Company, with an address of:

Twitter International Company   
Attn: Data Protection Officer   
One Cumberland Place, Fenian Street   
Dublin 2, D02 AX07 IRELAND 

If you are located in the European Economic Area, you can confidentially contact Twitter’s Data Protection Officer [here](https://twitter.ethicspointvp.com/custom/twitter/forms/data/form_data.asp). If you wish to raise a concern about our use of your information (and without prejudice to any other rights you may have), you have the right to do so with your local supervisory authority or Twitter International Company’s lead supervisory authority, the Irish Data Protection Commission. You can find their contact details [here](https://www.dataprotection.ie/docs/Contact-us/b/11.htm).

_Effective: May 25, 2018._
